Hi there, my name is Tashinga Mtoko.

I am a full-stack JavaScript developer with 4 years experience in working in Agile and Scrum environments, developing web-applications from design to consumer ready products for a variety of industries and clients. I am proficient in writing TypeScript and React js code, creating MERN and JAM stack applications, as well as working with the Google Cloud Platform through Firebase.

Working Experience

Aug 2021 - Present · 1 yr

Future Agent - Full-Stack Developer

- Helping lead development, software architecturing and organising roadmaps for our C2C (Customer-to-Customer) mobile application (<u>you can read the case study here</u>).
- Responsible for designing and currently maintaining our entire design system in Figma.
- Introduced and currently responsible for managing our React and design component libraries in Storybook (synced back to Figma).
- Introduced and currently spearheading the company's direction into using React js and TypeScript for all our products (we are currently using a combination of React, React Native and Next js for most of our products).

Nov 2021 - Jun 2022 · 8 mos

Beyond Architecture Real Estate - Web Developer and Designer

- Helped the different teams (a call centre sales team and the real estate agents) find better ways to communicate by introducing, integrating and training everyone across both teams on HubSpot (a CRM like SalesForce).
- As the only developer on the team, I developed the company's website (using Webflow) and integrated it to work and sync with their pre-existing realtor platforms.
- Introduced a host of their internal tools like Trello, time tracking tools like Clockify and Jibble as well as design tools like Canva (to help their marketing efforts after I left).
- Provided training and technical support for the different teams across the company.
- Created and maintained the company's design and brand guidelines.

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021 · 6 mos

Construct Education - Learning Technologist Tech Lead

- Introduced an atomic approach of creating custom CSS and JS components in the Canvas LMS (one of our main learning management platforms) through libraries like Tailwind CSS etc. (you can view the code for a small example of one of these components here).
- Took over the managing, cataloguing and integrating LTI's (which are basically plugins that are natively integrated into the learning platforms) across the company's Canvas LMS platform and select clients' platforms.
- Provided Canvas LMS and other technical support to the learning design and technology teams.
- Assisted with the technical on-boarding and training of the Canvas helpdesk support team (30 people) and select learning designers.
- Supported our sales and project management teams with creating a client quoting framework for Canvas LMS courses.

Oct 2019 - Sep 2020 · 1 yr

Construct Education - Learning Technologist (LT)

- Developed courses from the concepts our designers came up with and found ways to integrate them
 into our LMS platforms. Most notably, I created and integrated a way of creating branching paths in
 our Canvas LMS using JavaScript for a technology course for the Ross Business School in Michigan
 (you can view the code here).
- Worked directly with our partner institutions, providing technical support to their lecturers and staff. Most notably I became the first LT to be outsourced to work directly for one of our client institutions (the Saïd Business School in Oxford) at the beginning of the pandemic.
- Became the first person to be awarded the company's quarterly "Going the extra mile" award.

May 2020 - Apr 2021 · 1 yr

Leto - Designer/ Developer

- Designed and developed online stores and websites (using a combination of CMS platforms like Shopify, WordPress and Webflow with my HTML CSS and JavaScript skills) for our clients.
- Helped a number of our clients in establishing their online presences and finding better ways to
 manage their businesses. A notable example was when I created a recipe web-app for a client to help
 them protect their recipes, create membership access and save time from having to create PDF
 e-books every season.
- Provided technical support and developed business optimization solutions for our clients. A notable example was a bulk WhatsApp message sender and scheduler solution for a client who had been sending a lot of time sensitive messages manually.

Contact Info

Email: mtokotashinga@gmail.com
Phone number: +27 65 340 9650

Gifthub: ctasmto
Portfolio: tasmto.com
Linkedin: ctasmto
Based in: Cape Town

Languages & Frameworks

React.js | TypeScript | JavaScript | Next.js | Node.js | Express.js | Redux + Redux Toolkit & RTK Query | MongoDB | Mongoose | HTML | CSS | Sass | Git | GitHub | Google's Apps-Script | Tailwind CSS | MUI (Material UI) | Bootstrap.

Software Skills

VS Code I Adobe Photoshop, After Effects, XD & Premiere Pro I Figma I Sketch I Firebase I Sanity.io I WebFlow I WordPress I Shopify I Trello I Survey Monkey I Qualtrics I MailChimp.

Educational History

2020 · 1 year

Higher certificate in Web Design and Web Development at the Academy of Digital Arts

2019 · 1 year

Higher certificate in New Media Development at CityVarsity.

2017

Graduated from Milnerton High School.

Work Experiences contd.

Dec 2017 - Feb 2019 · 1 yr 3 mos

Monetise/ Brand Commerce - Digital Marketing Assistant

Nov 2017 – Feb 2019 · 1 yr 4 mos

Beauty Bulletin - Community Manager & Designer